A. Philip Randolph Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1909-1978 (Box 3-35)
  - "The Negro in Harlem," report, 1935
  - Prayer pilgrimage, 1957
    - Aims and purposes
    - Correspondence
    - Press releases
    - Printed matter
    - Program
  - President's Commission on Income Maintenance Programs, 1968-1969
  - Smear literature on civil rights movement, 1963, undated (Box 32)
  - Socialist Party, 1948-1971
  - State of the Race Conference, 1964
  - Thomas, Norman, 1954-1964
  - United Federation of Teachers, 1956, 1967-1968
  - Urban coalition, 1967-1968, undated
  - White House conferences
    - 1951-1952, Harry S. Truman
      - Correspondence, (3 folders)
      - Press releases
    - 1953-1959, Dwight D. Eisenhower
      - Correspondence, 1953-1959, undated, (2 folders)
      - Press release, 1958
    - 1965-1966, Lyndon B. Johnson, “ To Fulfill These Rights"
      - Administration of justice, 1966
      - Correspondence, 1965-1966, undated (Box 33)
      - Council meeting, 1966
      - Economic security and welfare, 1966
      - Health, 1966
      - Minutes, 1966
      - Planning sessions, 1965-1966, (5 folders)
      - Press releases, 1966, undated (Box 34)
      - Program, 1966
      - Report and recommendations, 1966
        - Drafts
          - May 6-8
          - May 14
          - June 23
          - Undated
        - Final version
      - Time schedule
  - Wills, 1958-1976, undated
  - Youth March for Integrated Schools
    - Citations, 1958, undated
    - Clippings, 1958
    - Correspondence, 1958-1959, undated, (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Finances, 1949-1959, undated
    - Meetings, 1958-1959, undated
    - Miscellany, 1958-1959, undated
    - Organizing manuals, 1958-1959
    - Pledges and resolutions, 1959, undated
    - Presidential delegation, 1959, undated
    - Printed matter, undated
    - Program, 1958-1959, undated
    - Sponsors, 1958-1959
    - Statements and press releases, 1958-1959, undated
- Speeches and Writings File, 1917-1978 (Box 35-43)
  Typewritten drafts and near-print copies of speeches, articles, an autobiographical essay, statements, remarks, and miscellaneous related matter.
  Articles are arranged alphabetically and research notes and related material, speaking engagements, and speeches chronologically.
  - Articles (Box 35)
    - 1917, 1936-1943, 1952, 1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - Undated (Box 36)
  - Autobiographical essay, “Vita,” undated
  - Fragments, undated
  - Research notes and related material, 1942-1945, 1953-1969, undated, (5 folders); (8 folders); (3 folders) (Box 37, Box 38)
  - Speaking engagements
    - Correspondence, 1947-1975, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1940, 1978
  - Speeches (Box 39)
    - 1941-1957, (17 folders)
    - 1958-1962, (8 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1962-1966, (7 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1967-1978, (8 folders) (Box 42)
    - Undated, (6 folders); (10 folders) (Box 43)
- Biographical File, 1945-1979 (Box 44-46)
  Interviews, notes, printed matter, and other biographical material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Interviews, notes, and other information, 1957-1978, undated, (6 folders) (Box 44)
  - Printed matter
    - 1945-1966, (4 folders)
    - 1967-1979, undated, (7 folders) (Box 45)
  - Profiles and notes, 1943-1979, undated, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 46)
- Miscellany, 1920-1979 (Box 46-56)
  Address books, appointment books, scrapbooks, awards, certificate, miscellany, telephone directories, press releases, printed matter, shorthand notebooks, and travel documents.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Address books, 1968, undated (Box 46)
  - Appointment books
    - 1960-1962, (3 folders)
    - 1963-1965, (4 folders) (Box 47)
    - 1966, (1 folder) (Box 48)
    - 1967-1969, (4 folders)
    - 1970-1975, (6 folders) (Box 49)
    - 1976-1978, (3 folders) (Box 50)
  - Awards
    - Certificate, 1928
    - Honorary degrees, 1959-1977, undated
    - Invitations to serve as chairman or sponsor
      - 1942-1967, (2 folders)
      - 1968-1979, undated, (4 folders) (Box 51)
  - Miscellany, 1928-1978
  - Personal telephone directories, undated, (1 folder) (Box 52)
  - Press releases, 1940-1979, undated, (6 folders)
  - Printed matter
    - 1926-1951, (2 folders)
    - 1954-1960, (5 folders) (Box 53)
    - 1960-1964, (5 folders) (Box 54)
  - Printed matter (Box 55)
    - 1965-1969, undated, (7 folders)
  - Scrapbooks, 1920-1946 See Oversize, (4 vols.) (Box 56)
  - Travel documents, passport, itineraries, and receipts, 1951-1966
  - Wilds, Bernice Greene, shorthand notebooks, 1948-1949, 1968-1969
- Oversize, 1920-1946 (Box OV 1-4)
  Scrapbooks.
  Arranged and described according to the series and containers from which the items were removed.
  - Scrapbooks (Container 56) (Box OV 1)
    - 1920-1943
    - 1940-1944 (Box OV 2)
    - 1941-1943 (Box OV 3)
    - 1943-1946 (Box OV 4)